Pratisha Barman

A dedicated and result-driven project management professional with over 4 years of experience in project management and project control, offering a well-rounded skill set that encompasses Strategic Discussions, Business Intelligence, Project Management, Tendering, Bidding, Procurement, and Documentation.

Known for relentless work ethics, I am committed to delivering outcomes that exceed expectations, underpinned by strong analytical skills and the ability to excel in situations with minimal direction.

Also, been part of the organization's key initiatives, such as implementing the project communication tool-Aconex and launching ESG (Environmental, Social and Governance) initiatives with a 1 year roadmap.

Contact Information

Email id:

pratisha.barman28@gmail.com

Contact No:

9101155608

Technical Skills

- Aconex
- Microsoft Projects
- Primavera
- Microsoft Power Point
- Microsoft Excel
- Microsoft Word

Soft Skills

- Communication Skills
- Stakeholder Management
- Detail Oriented
- Problem Solving
- Microsoft Excel
- Microsoft Word

Education Background

2020: PGPM in Project Engineering and Management – NICMAR, Pune

2017: Bachelors in Mechanical Engineering- Nagpur University

Achievements

2023: Selected and underwent prestigious Future's Network-Leadership Program with Welspun One

2022: Won Star of the quarter for 2 consecutive quarters at Welspun One

2020: Certified Associate in Project Management

Professional Experience

Welspun One Logistics Parks- Mumbai| Assistant Manager

2022 - Present

Demonstrated adaptability in overseeing diverse projects, spanning from strategic discussions to procurement and documentation, ensuring efficient project lifecycles.

Led the deployment of Aconex, a communication and collaboration tool, enhancing project communication and documentation management and workflows

Interacted with clients, JV Partners, and investors as an SPOC on behalf of CDO and managed preliminary-level problem-solving and relationship management.

Created and implemented SOPs and workflows for smoothening and optimization of processes in the organization.

Developed and implemented the ESG roadmap, aligning the organization with sustainability goals and corporate responsibility initiatives Excelled in project management, tracking project progress, risk assessment, and mitigation strategies, highlighting issues, and problem-solving ensuring projects stay on course and on budget.

Recognized for effective communication skills and the ability to foster collaboration among cross-functional teams, resulting in streamlined project execution and smooth Stakeholder management Prepared Management Committee decks along with planning for organisational structure and resource allotment at sites

Blue Star Limited-Mumbai| Senior Engineer

2021-2022

Successfully managed project bids and tendering processes, consistently securing projects that contributed to the organization's growth.

Understanding the bidding process for Rural/Urban water supply and municipal water treatment along with project monitoring for 3 projects altogether and did the entire site mobilisation and ensured vendor payments on time

Technical bid preparation for all projects with nil errors helping team to upload the jobs on SAP.

Controlling all important statutory documents and keeping up-to-date documents required for the commercial part of bid submission.

Advise businesses to buy or sell products on Market insights

Freelancing-Pune | Project Planner

2019-2021

Freelanced as a project planner while scheduling projects on MSP and Primavera for local contractors

Prepared presentations and helped in resource allotment and standardizing the formats for DPR

Internship

AMs Project Consultants, Pune

Summer Intern- April'19-June'19